<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.kde.kreversi.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="hi">के-रिवर्सी</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Reversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr">К‑реверси</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr-Latn">K‑reversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr-ijekavian">К‑реверси</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr-ijekavianlatin">K‑reversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Othello</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKReversixx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">KReversi</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">KReversi</name>
  <summary>Reversi Board Game</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Joc de taula Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Joc de taula Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Desková hra Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">„Reversi“-Brettspiel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Reversi Board Game</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Juego de mesa Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Reversi lauamäng</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">«Reversi» mahai-jokoa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Reversi-lautapeli</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Jeu de plateau Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Xogo de taboleiro similar ao Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hi">रिवर्सी बोर्ड खेल</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Permainan Papan Membalik-balik</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Gioco da tavolo tipo Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">리버시 보드 게임</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Reversi-bordspel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Brettspelet reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Gra planszowa Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Jogo de Tabuleiro Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Jogo de tabuleiro Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Joc de table Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Настольная игра «Реверси»</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Stolová hra Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Namizna igra Reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr">Игра на табли реверси</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr-Latn">Igra na tabli reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr-ijekavian">Игра на табли реверси</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr-ijekavianlatin">Igra na tabli reversi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Othello brädspel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Reversi Tahta Oyunu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Гра на дошці (реверсі)</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxReversi Board Gamexx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">黑白棋游戏</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      KReversi is a simple one player strategy game played against the computer.
      If a player's piece is captured by an opposing player, that piece is turned over
      to reveal the color of that player. A winner is declared when one player has more
      pieces of his own color on the board and there are no more possible moves.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El KReversi és un joc senzill d'estratègia per a jugar individualment contra l'ordinador. Si una peça del jugador és capturada per un contrari, la peça es girarà per a mostrar el color d'aquest jugador. Es guanya la partida quan un jugador té més peces del seu color en el tauler i no hi ha més moviments possibles.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El KReversi és un joc senzill d'estratègia per a jugar individualment contra l'ordinador. Si una peça del jugador és capturada per un contrari, la peça es girarà per a mostrar el color d'aquest jugador. Es guanya la partida quan un jugador té més peces del seu color en el tauler i no hi ha més moviments possibles.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">KReversi ist ein einfaches Strategiespiel für einen Spieler, der gegen den Computer spielt. Falls ein Spieler einen gegnerischen Stein auf dem Brett erobert, wird dieser umgedreht und gehört diesem Spieler. Gewonnen hat, wer am meisten Steine seiner Farbe auf dem Brett hat, wenn kein weiterer Stein mehr gesetzt werden kann.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">KReversi is a simple one player strategy game played against the computer. If a player's piece is captured by an opposing player, that piece is turned over to reveal the colour of that player. A winner is declared when one player has more pieces of his own colour on the board and there are no more possible moves.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">KReversi es un sencillo juego de estrategia para un único jugador que juega contra la computadora. Si una ficha de un jugador es capturada por el oponente, cambia al color de ese oponente. El ganador será el jugador que tenga más fichas de su propio color sobre el tablero cuando no existan más movimientos posibles.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">KReversi on lihtne ühe mängijaga arvuti vastu mängitav strateegiamäng. Kui vastane hõivab teise nupu, siis võtab hõivatud nupp hõivaja nuppude värvi. Mängu võitja selgub siis, kui ühel mängijal on enda värvi nuppe mänguväljakul rohkem kui vastasel ning enam pole kellelgi võimalik kuhugi käia.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eu">KReversi ordenagailuaren aurka jokatutako jokalari bakarreko estrategia-joko bat da. Jokalari baten pieza aurkariak harrapatzen badu, pieza horri buelta ematen zaio aurkariaren kolorea erakusteko. Jokalari batek irabazten du, beste mugimendurik egiterik ez dagoenean, taulan bere koloreko pieza gehiago dituenean.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">KReversi on yksinkertainen yhden pelaajan strateginen lautapeli tietokonetta vastaan. Jos vastustaja kaappaa pelaajan nappulan, se käännetään, jolloin paljastuu vastustajan väri. Kun siirtoja ei voi enää tehdä, voittajaksi selviää se, jolla on enemmän omanvärisiään nappuloita.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">KReversi est un jeu de stratégie simple à un joueur qui se joue contre l'ordinateur. Si une pièce du joueur est capturée par un adversaire, cette pièce change de couleur pour prendre celle du joueur. Un gagnant est déclaré lorsqu'un joueur a plus de pièces de sa propre couleur que son adversaire et qu'il n'y a plus de mouvements possibles.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">KReversi é un xogo de estratexia sinxelo para un único xogador que se enfronta ao computador. Se o opoñente captura a peza do xogador, a peza entrégase para descubrir a cor do xogador. O gañador declárase cando un dos xogadores ten máis pezas da súa cor no taboleiro e non hai máis movementos posíbeis.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">KReversi adalah permainan strategi satu pemain sederhana yang dimainkan melawan komputer. Jika potongan pemain ditangkap oleh pemain lawan, potongan itu dibalik untuk mengungkapkan warna pemain itu. Pemenang telah dinyatakan ketika satu pemain memiliki lebih banyak potongan warna sendiri di papan dan tidak ada gerakan lebih yang mungkin dilakukan.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">KReversi è un semplice gioco di strategia a un giocatore che si gioca contro il computer. Se il pezzo del giocatore viene catturato dall'avversario, il pezzo viene girato per mostrare il colore dell'avversario. Viene dichiarato vincitore il giocatore che ha sulla scacchiera più pezzi del proprio colore e nessun'altra mossa è possibile.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">KReversi는 컴퓨터와 플레이할 수 있는 1인용 전략 게임입니다. 다른 플레이어가 플레이어의 돌을 잡으면 돌을 뒤집어서 색을 바꿉니다. 판이 가득 찼을 때 판에 있는 돌의 색이 더 많은 플레이어가 이깁니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KReversi is een eenvoudig strategiespel dat u tegen de computer speelt. Als een steen van een speler wordt gevangen door een tegenstander, dan wordt de steen omgedraaid en de kleur ervan verandert in die van de tegenstander. De winnaar wordt uitgeroepen als een van de spelers meer stenen in zijn kleur op het bord heeft en er geen zetten meer mogelijk zijn.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nn">KReversi er eit enkelt strategispel for éin spelar mot datamaskina. Når ein spelar tek ei av brikkene til motstandaren, vert ho snudd slik at fargen til spelaren vert synleg. Vinnaren vert kåra når ein spelar har flest brikker i sin farge og det ikkje lenger finst nokon moglege trekk.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">KReversi jest prostą jednoosobową grą strategiczną przeciwko komputerowi. Jeśli pionek gracza zostanie zbity przez przeciwnika, to pionek ten zostaje obrócony, aby ujawnić barwę tego gracza. Zwycięzcą zostaje ten kto ma najwięcej pionków własnej barwy na planszy w chwiili gdy nie będzie możliwy żaden ruch.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O KReversi é um jogo simples de estratégia para um jogador contra o computador. Se a peça de um jogador é capturada por um jogador adversário, essa peça é virada para revelar a cor desse jogador. É declarado um vencedor quando um jogador tem mais peças da sua própria cor no tabuleiro e não existem mais jogadas possíveis.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KReversi é um jogo simples de estratégia para um jogador que pratica contra o computador. Se uma peça for capturada por um jogador adversário, essa peça é virada para revelar a cor desse jogador. É declarado um vencedor quando esse jogador ficar com mais peças da sua cor no tabuleiro e se não existirem mais jogadas possíveis.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">KReversi je jednoduchá hra pre jedného hráča proti počítaču. Ak kamene hráča vezme protihráč, kamene zmenia farbu na farbu oponenta. Víťazom sa stane hráč, ktorý má viac kameňov svojej farby na ploche a nie sú možné ďalšie pohyby.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">KReversi je preprosta enoigralska strateška igra, ki se igra proti računalniku. Če nasprotni igralec zavzame vaš žeton, se ta obrne in razkrije barve nasprotnika. Ko ni več veljavnih potez, je igre konec, zmaga pa tisti, ki ima več žetonov njegove barve.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">К‑реверси је једноставна стратешка игра за једног играча, који игра против рачунара. Када противнички играч зароби играчеву фигуру, та фигура се преврће да открије боју тог играча. Победник је онај играч који има више фигура своје боје на табли када више не може да се повуче ниједан потез.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr-Latn">K‑reversi je jednostavna strateška igra za jednog igrača, koji igra protiv računara. Kada protivnički igrač zarobi igračevu figuru, ta figura se prevrće da otkrije boju tog igrača. Pobednik je onaj igrač koji ima više figura svoje boje na tabli kada više ne može da se povuče nijedan potez.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr-ijekavian">К‑реверси је једноставна стратешка игра за једног играча, који игра против рачунара. Када противнички играч зароби играчеву фигуру, та фигура се преврће да открије боју тог играча. Победник је онај играч који има више фигура своје боје на табли када више не може да се повуче ниједан потез.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr-ijekavianlatin">K‑reversi je jednostavna strateška igra za jednog igrača, koji igra protiv računara. Kada protivnički igrač zarobi igračevu figuru, ta figura se prevrće da otkrije boju tog igrača. Pobednik je onaj igrač koji ima više figura svoje boje na tabli kada više ne može da se povuče nijedan potez.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Othello är ett enkelt strategispel för en spelare som spelas mot datorn. Om en pjäs tas av motspelaren, vänds den för att visa motspelarens färg. Vinnaren utses när en spelare har fler pjäser med sin färg på brädet och inga fler drag är möjliga.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">KReversi bilgisayara karşı oynanan basit bir, tek oyunculu strateji oyunudur. Bir oyuncunun taşı karşı taraf oyuncusu tarafından yakalanırsa, o oyuncunun rengi açığa çıkarmak için o taş devredilir. Kazanan, bir oyuncunun tahtadaki kendi taşından daha fazla oyuna sahip olması ve daha fazla hamle bulunmaması durumunda ilan edilir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KReversi — проста стратегічна гра для одного гравця, суперником якого буде комп’ютер. Якщо фішка поміняє власника, її буде перевернуто, і вона показуватиме колір гравця-власника. Переможцем проголошується той з гравців, у якого буде більше власних фішок за такої позиції у грі, коли подальші ходи будуть неможливими.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKReversi is a simple one player strategy game played against the computer. If a player's piece is captured by an opposing player, that piece is turned over to reveal the color of that player. A winner is declared when one player has more pieces of his own color on the board and there are no more possible moves.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">KReversi 是一个简单的与计算机对战的单机策略游戏。 如果玩家的一块被对方玩家夺取，那块将被翻转来显示该玩家的颜色。 当一个玩家在棋盘上拥有更多的自己的颜色并且没有更多可能的落子时，赢家诞生。</p>
  </description>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kreversi</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.kde.org/?application=kreversi</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.kde.org/community/donations/?app=kreversi&amp;source=appdata</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/kreversi/kreversi.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kreversi</binary>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="2.1.21080" date="2021-08-12"/>
    <release version="2.1.21043" date="2021-07-08"/>
    <release version="2.1.21042" date="2021-06-10"/>
    <release version="2.1.21041" date="2021-05-13"/>
  </releases>
</component>
